let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1.,
        question: 'User can make any change on image with the use of ',
        answer: 'B. Interactive graphics',
        options: [
            'A. Non-interactive graphics',
            'B. Interactive graphics',
            'C. Both 1 & 2',
            'D. None of these'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2.,
        question: 'Which method are used to get and set the position of a pixel, object or text in active area of a desktop',
        answer: 'A. Basic positioning method',
        options: [
            'A. Basic positioning method',
            'B. Sketching method',
            'C. Gravity field method',
            'D. None of these'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3.,
        question: '	In a raster scan method for transformation, a 900 rotation can be performed by?',
        answer: 'C. by coping each row of the block into a column in the new frame buffer location',
        options: [
            'A. reversing the order of bits within each row in the frame buffer',
            'B. by performing XOR on the frame buffer location',
            'C. by coping each row of the block into a column in the new frame buffer location',
            'D. None of above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4.,
        question: 'Why a circle drawn on the screen appears to be elleptical?',
        answer: 'A. It is due to the aspect ratio of monitor',
        options: [
            'A. It is due to the aspect ratio of monitor',
            'B. Screen has rectangular shape',
            'C. Our eyes are not at the same level on screen',
            'D. CRT is completely spherical'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5.,
        question: 'Which is the following technique is used in Midpoint Subdivision algorithm?',
        answer: 'C. Heap sort',
        options: [
            'A. Linear search',
            'B. Binary search',
            'C. Heap sort',
            'D. Bubble sort'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6.,
        question: 'What is the ideal resolution of an image for web.',
        answer: 'A. 72 PPI',
        options: [
            'A. 72 PPI',
            'B. 300 PPI',
            'C. 100 PPI',
            'D. 250 PPI'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7.,
        question: 'A good example of hypermedia in actual use is:',
        answer: 'A. The internet',
        options: [
            'A. The internet',
            'B. Level I video disc',
            'C. Videotape',
            'D. Audiotape'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8.,
        question: 'Hardware that creates sound from a mathematics representation',
        answer: 'A. Sound Synthesizer',
        options: [
            'A. Sound Synthesizer',
            'B. Stampers',
            'C. Speaker',
            'D. Sons'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9.,
        question: 'Each set of bit pattern is called',
        answer: 'A. code.',
        options: [
            'A. code.',
            'B. unicode.',
            'C. coding',
            'D. ascii'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10.,
        question: 'Unsigned representation of numbers by one complement can represent',
        answer: 'C. positive and negative number',
        options: [
            'A. positive number',
            'B. negative number',
            'C. positive and negative number',
            'D. infinite numbers'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11.,
        question: 'In synthetic curves, zero-order continuity yields',
        answer: 'A. a position continuous curve',
        options: [
            'A. a position continuous curve',
            'B. a slope continuous curve',
            'C. a curvature continuous curve',
            'D. none of above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12.,
        question: 'Projection rays(projectors) emanate from a ',
        answer: 'C. Both 1 & 2',
        options: [
            'A. COP(centre of projection)',
            'B. Intersect proj78ection plane',
            'C. Both 1 & 2',
            'D. None of these'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13.,
        question: 'The curves displayed with a rectangular pen will be',
        answer: 'B. Thicker and magnitude slope is 1',
        options: [
            'A. Thinner',
            'B. Thicker and magnitude slope is 1',
            'C. Thicker and magnitude slope > 1',
            'D. 2 or 3'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14.,
        question: 'A translation is applied to an object by',
        answer: 'A. Repositioning it along with straight line path',
        options: [
            'A. Repositioning it along with straight line path',
            'B. Repositioning it along with circular path',
            'C. Only 2',
            'D. All of the mentioned'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15.,
        question: 'We translate a two-dimensional point by adding',
        answer: 'D. Only 1',
        options: [
            'A. Translation distances',
            'B. Translation difference',
            'C. X and Y',
            'D. Only 1'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16.,
        question: 'If the value of sx=1 and sy=1 then',
        answer: 'D. No change in the size of an object',
        options: [
            'A. Reduce the size of object',
            'B. Distort the picture',
            'C. Produce an enlargement',
            'D. No change in the size of an object'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17.,
        question: 'Shadow mark method is used in -',
        answer: 'A. Raster scan system',
        options: [
            'A. Raster scan system',
            'B. Random scan system',
            'C. Both (1) & (2)',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18.,
        question: 'A homogeneous coordinate is represented by a ___________',
        answer: 'A. Triplet',
        options: [
            'A. Triplet',
            'B. Quadruplet',
            'C. Tetractic',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19.,
        question: '________ algorithm is orientation dependent.',
        answer: 'A. DDA',
        options: [
            'A. DDA',
            'B. Rasterization',
            'C. Scan conversion',
            "D. Bresenham's Lane Algorithm"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20.,
        question: 'Trackball is',
        answer: 'C. Pointer device',
        options: [
            'A. Two-dimensional postioning device',
            'B. Three-dimensional positioning device',
            'C. Pointer device',
            'D. None of the mentioned'
        ]
    }
]